# Malcolm MacLure

Full-Stack Web Developer

905-510-5096 malcolm.maclure@gmail.com www.malcolmmaclure.com

### Summary

I am a web developer with a background in international culture and business, and a drive to create elegant designs with clean, precise code. I have a passion for solutions that centre on human experience, expression, and empathy.

## **Technologies**

HTML React
CSS Redux
Sass Ruby
Javascript Python
ES6 Django
SVG Rails

Git PostgreSQL

### Skills

Project Management
Team Management
Public Speaking
Photoshop
Illustrator
InDesign
Japanese (N2 - advanced)
French (intermediate)

### Education

Bitmaker General Assembly Web Development Immersive

Mount Allison University Bachelor of Arts: World Religions, Asian Studies / History

### Experience

#### WEB DEVELOPMENT IMMERSIVE

General Assembly Bitmaker | Toronto, ON | Nov 2018 - Feb 2019

 Built fluency in full-stack web development through completing an intensive full-time three-month program focused on common best practices in paradigms including:

OOP | MVC frameworks | RESTful APIs | TDD | Agile development

#### NATIONAL PROGRAMME COORDINATOR

Embassy of Japan in Canada | Ottawa, ON | 2014 - Sep 2018

- Product Manager: Implemented UI features for an Applicant Tracking System used by the Japanese embassies in Canada and the US (20k+ applicants annually) resulting in 10%+ increased conversion rate and 20%+ reduction in application processing time
- Website and Social Media Manager: Built programme's website using Wordpress (www.jetprogramme.ca), and increased followers on Facebook (3k+ followers) and Twitter (1k+ followers), by 10%+ each
- Team Leader: Trained and managed teams of 5 people to process high-volume applications from across Canada (2k applications over 3 months), trained teams of 10 people for 4 corporate training events attended by 50 people
- Event Planner: Planned 8 formal events hosted by the ambassador of Japan (100+ attendees), planned 4 weekend-long all-day interview events each consisting of 3 panels of 3 evaluators for 50+ candidates
- Public Speaker: MC at embassy cultural event (10k+ attendees), gave 10 tourism and recruitment presentations attended by 100 attendees

#### RECRUITMENT CONSULTANT

Recruiting In Motion | Mississauga, ON | 2014

- Strengthened relationships with strategic and emerging partners through meetings with senior leadership
- Ensured smooth on-boarding by follow-up calls and meetings with clients and new hires

#### ASSOCIATE RECRUITMENT CONSULTANT

East West Consulting | Tokyo, Japan | 2012 - 2013

- Interviewed 400+ candidates within 12 months
- Placed candidates resulting in company earnings of \$50,000+ (¥4.5M)
- Created job transitioning reference materials for candidates resulting in reduced candidate churn